most pursued high risk was of course the
payments receivable risk which is and
the second risk was of course the Cyber
fraud risk so these are two very
important aspects the other traditional
policies are also available as you know
Factory related policies and employee
health but these were the two very
recently highlighted which have got lot
of tractions from the business owner
survey one as I told you one was the
Cyber fraud risk and the other is
related to payments receivable right
thank you next slide
so right so here we are here to tell you
as to so normally when business owners
take decisions on risk so which is also
called as risk management they decide
what risk needs to be retained by
risk you can do away without transfer
some risk they identify which can hit
the balance sheet though they normally
try to pass it on to insurance companies
in the form of insurance which is
basically when you transfer the
risk and of course as you understand the
entire concept of insurance works
on premium collect which may be good
enough to pay off claims for one or two
people which who may claim during the
year this is how the concept of
insurance works why I kept this slide is
because the idea is that mostly when you
take risk related decisions you bucket
the risk which you want to transfer the
risk whether you wish to retain the risk
because you see that there is no pursued
element of risk is not financially
impact but as you feel that the risk
magude you may always try to review it
and transfer it out to an insurance
company in the form of insurance
contract thank
you next
slide right so here as I told you
what are the risk which are exposed to
of course the building planted Machinery
the office assets and stocks uh because
these are high value items uh which are
running around the clock and especially
in plastic related Industries where
there is Hazard because it's a
petrochemical with product with high BTU
which is British thermal unit which we
call as to identify what is the
probability of fire or other related
losses so what is the uh uh next point
so what is the risk that is exposed to
to these buildings planting machineries
and stocks there is risk of fire flood
earthquake as you all know that these
are Act of God perils similarly there's
a breakdown of machines risk especially
to the Extrusion process machineries
including to the blow molding process or
in injection molding process so it's is
the
solutionset solutions simple
policy the regulator the iida has broken
down the fire policy into bhat sukma
udyam bat lagu udam and standard fire
and special Paris policy companies who
wish to have higher higher coverages can
also go for industrial loss of
industrial allrisk policy similarly
industrial o risk also has Provisions to
cover loss of profit insurance which I
told you is very critical and
important mostfa
mostly single
block ra material finished goods or
dispatches processing everything is in
one single block and
plasticard important that you always
have a loss of profit Insurance because
this policy is now available as an
independent cover also in the Indian
market then the other aspect of course
is the Machinery breakdown policy and
also burglary and theft policy so I'll
also highlight because uh here uh uh
there's a development in the industry
effective 1 April
2024 the regulator which is iida has
scrapped the minimum pricing of I so
it's a very welcome move for the
industry there is no regulated pricing
for fire insurance discounts are
available applicable on your fire flexa
rates is what we call us and it can go
up to any percentage depend up
percentage of discount but it all
depends upon what kind of risk
management practices what kind of
housekeeping facilities what kind of
firefighting uh facilities installations
you have the more the risk better the
risk management of course you will be uh
allowed or entitled for maximum discount
so here I'll tell you uh why as a
company also we tried and focus only on
doing a plastic Insurance uh business
because we we realized over a period of
time there were four or five challenges
in the industry of course first was uh a
lot of these plastic companies being
msme units the fire fighting and other
risk management practices are normally
not up to the mark As per the as as the
insurance company's expectation is is uh
so here we have seen lot of distress
settlements of claims also uh wherein
once there is a law the insurance
companies and surveyors normally uh tend
to try to cut corners
uh citing either some flaws in
documentation or msme mostly msmes do
business to make profits and run their
businesses and expand their businesses
sometimes all your books and accounting
practices may not
be for example or insurance companies
try to uh non-standardized that claim at
times reject the claim so so that's why
addressing these challenges we have we
have tied up with the insurance
companies with slas on these challenges
which are W which means insurance
companies will not ask for those
documents because
contant Reas
like accounting practices second
machiner
invoicing assets are not fully
capitalized so we have got relevant
drafting which we can help you to ensure
that uh your claims are maximized and
settled in order this is the first the
second slide
please of course uh the second uh slide
is about Goods in transit of course lot
of movement of goods happen either in
form of purchases locally or import of
goods I me now to so there's lot of
again supply chain disruptions which we
are seeing in our clients and our lot of
our clients especially in petrochemical
products are resting to uh bulk uh cargo
Imports uh of course bulk cargo Imports
come with their own challenges related
to losses because storages or handling
losses but especially if I talk about
containerized cargo to the exposure of
course is plastic related Commodities it
is all your raw materials it can also be
your capital goods which you import and
what is the risk we all understand
there's a Goods in transit risk it can
it is
susceptable Rec for stationary we
settled a claim for 3.34 crores which
was a general average claim normally
Plastics clients
domestic reca
which was related to Imports of cargo
wherein there was a general average
claim there was claim on the entire
vessel so that is called as a general
average apart from that to tell you very
frequently we have seen claims of theft
uh in fact we have got another claim of
a there was a fire in the transporter go
down because on the movementa there are
lot of various shipments which
happen and it is up to your transporter
for those movement of goods so these are
susceptible to Risk Solutions available
Indian market of course Marine cargo
Insurance either you can break it down
you can take separate policies for
export import domestic sales yeah
domestic purchase or else you can also
buy an advanced version of policy which
is available now in the Indian market
which is called as the marine sales
turnover policy which is a single policy
for all your supply chain risk issues uh
it's a 360° cover for as I told you for
your purchase Imports container
movements uh inter Depot inter Depot
movements yeah inter Factory movements
job Works uh capital goods all can be
combined under one single policy and
most importantly we in this section we
have got some filed add-on covers uh
which are which cover over and above the
base policy like we have seen shortage
from seal intact containers
especially shortage so shortage from
seed intact containers are also covered
so what we have done with our more than
18 years of experience in the industry
we have devised add-on covers just say
Claims can be either rejected or become
nonp payable and we have asked insurer
to cover them in the form of add-on
covers similarly there are covers like
sellers contingency cover which is
available or a concealed damage Clause
uh which can be taken uh to ensure that
your Marine Sales turnover policy
coverage is comprom comprehensively
designed yes next slide please
thanks the third aspect is of course the
employee health and safety very
important uh employees uh even so in
manufacturing industry especially in the
last 3 four years we have seen a lot of
realization on uh the kind of benefit
should what should be offered we have
been asked to Benchmark uh the uh
policies uh vises the competition and
the industry so of course the exposed
are the payroll employees and also the
contractual employees uh they are of
course exposed to any disease or any
injury uh especially the senior manag
the the the administrative staff to uh
there are lifestyle diseases these days
uh the people on the to are exposed to
because they are machinist labors and
they are exposed to handling hazards
also and the solutions which are
available in the industry now is the
health insurance policy the accident
insurance and Workman so after the covid
the ministry of Home Affairs had issued
a circular for workers to come
backed
policy contractual workers insurance so
those kind of and this can be customized
to any extent what kind of some insure
what kind of family benefits you wish to
have so again very important aspect when
you uh do the risk management because it
is the plant and the people who will
take you to the next level is what I
feel uh and of course people are very
relevant in this process so uh employee
benefits uh insurance will help you here
right thank you next
slide right so this is again a very
important uh product especially in the
export market so if you see if if you
have got contracts from outside India
especially the American in the Europe
Market they will always ask you to
supply a product liability or a
comprehensive general liability
insurance to be in place because what
happens is as a manufacturer of the
product ultimately if there's any bodily
injury or property damage product use
final use once it goes out in the market
the the the liability is always on the
manufacturer it can come back to you
with the forward chain forward super
stock is distrib
but what happens it can always come back
to the original manufacturer especially
in flexible packaging fibc we have seen
lot of notifications uh related to uh
claims coming in this segment and of
course the solutions which are available
is the product liability which covers
you for body injury and property damage
but we have also taken it to the next
level and given covers like product
recall sometimes it may so happen that
if a particular defect batch your
product the entire lot can be rejected
your future Lots can be rejected so
recall Works in this case if your
primary cover is Avail primary cover
trigger policy claim recall cover is
also covered in fact product guarantee
is also covered product guarantee is
nothing but
product the answer of course is
comprehensive general liability which
again uh is applicable uh for such
defective products and product failures
thank you next
slide cyber I Told You So as we talk
about machine learning artificial
intelligence deployments of lot of these
uh computer and it assets so uh so once
we do all these system Integrations uh
to ensure that we get the right amount
of and correct amount of data so that
decision making can possible but here
somewhere we are also making us
vulnerable to risk related to hacking
ransomware uh business interruptions so
very recently there was a manufacturing
company which was which was a fully
automated plant which was controlled
only by six people and their main sock
was in Italy uh the the hackers got
control of the entire system their
systems were hacked and there was denial
of access
production and they had put some request
of Ransom and which was
subsequently uh handled and addressed
through insurance company because lot of
times it is not only about insurance is
not about only paying claims insurance
companies help you get right people at
the back end who are specialist in the
subject who can negotiate on your behalf
who can ensure that your claims are not
uh getting Beyond hands and the they
they ensure that the claims management
is there and also they uh help you in
the uh reimbursement or financial
settlement of the loss which you incur
because of these uh RIS and of course
the solutions which are available is
cyber liability uh one aspect which I'm
not uh covered here is also very
important but not available nowadays
very easily in Indian market is the
crime
insurance manufacturing
companies locations Factor where the
business owners are sitting so sometimes
we have seen some kind
of if there's any fraud or any uh any
any anything which is not happening as
per the normal so such kind of crime uh
related Financial loss is also covered
under the Cyber and crime insurance
cover right thank
you right this is the crime insurance
cover which as I was talking about of
course I've covered this uh so we we
will skip this
thank you next
slide right so what we bring to the
table before I give you to Sachin uh so
one of the USPS what we do is uh we we
help you in gap analysis audit of your
existing insurance policies to identify
if there's any flaw in the policy if
there's any error omission of Clauses uh
like very frequently we have seen
reinstatement value Clause missing in
the policies or or maybe we also help
you present what kind of uh forward or
upgraded versions available for those
your products second we have got some
very specific industry relevant add-on
covers like spontaneous combustion
static charge miscellanous assets which
are not capitalized again can be covered
under our policies we help you in
reinstatement valuation which is nothing
but uh ensuring that your assets are
insured for reinstatement value which is
again one of the USPS of fire policies
available in India
but to ensure the gross block values or
wdv of course will not help you you have
to get the right valuation done so we
have inow Valu us which will help which
will help you to get you the right
valuations apart from that because uh
because as I told you all these
discounting and pricing will all depend
upon how well you manage your risk so we
also do fire safety Audits and
thermography including energ efficiency
audit which will help you to so once the
implementation is done it will help you
uh to get better discounting in pricing
one aspect but the other aspect is see
no one wants claim so if you want to
ensure that the best of the risk
management is in place such activities
will ensure your electrical your
maintenance team will work on those
audit reports your findings
thermography C hotot identify so your
electrical maintenance team can work on
those audit reports and correct uh and
rectify this we also do mock call to
ensure
insur or whether you as a company is
ready for those kind of
documents thanks uh next
slide so this is a very this is the last
Slide the claims which we believe is the
moment of truth and efficient claims
management is our USP and uh we are
based out of Mumbai as I told you with a
team we have dedicated teams in know for
underwriting claims policy operations we
specialize in plastic processing
Industries including Master batches
additives uh pipes and striding
stationaries and uh so we will be
involved right from documentation
drafting uh settlement uh with insurance
companies and negotiations with
surveyors so this is what we do we have
settled close to 10,000 claims um of
course majorly being employee benefits
but property claims are also around 22
crores
22% uh till datee the the the biggest
CLA which we have settled to the tune of
55 crores for a plastic manufacturing
company uh so and we'll be happy to
share more details uh if someone wishes
to uh during the presentation if there
are any questions please pop up with
this I think I will rest my presentation
and hand over to the P to Mr uh sain to
take it forward for
us thanks uh thanks prmod G for giving
me this opportunity thanks Plex
committee also for
setting up this program and a warm good
evening for to all the
attendees uh so you just can move on to
the next
slide yes so basically Credit Insurance
While most of the or or few of the
attendees might be aware of what it is
but for a larger audience we are
basically here talking about covering
your unsecured accounts receivable
especially when it comes to exports uh
you may or may not know the party to
whom you are exporting and giving a
credit to them will lead to a risk of a
commercial default or because of
political event default or delay in
payment and that is where the credit
Insurance uh comes in picture it not
only covers insolvency of the buyer so
you have an exposure on a buyer and the
buyer has got insolvent that event is
also covered as well as if there is a
delay in payment when we say delay in
payment we are talking about a time line
specified in the insurance policy that
within this much time if you have not
received the payment then it is eligible
for a claim irrespective of whether the
buyer is insolvent or not and once you
file a claim then from there initially
insurance company will take an effort to
recover the money and there also we will
have a defined timeline which is defined
in the policy and subsequently if
recovery has happened that would reduce
your debt if recovery has not happened
or partial recovery has happened then
insurance company will pay pay out a
claim from their own pockets and next
risk which we are talking about is
political risk where because of certain
political conditions in the home country
of the buyer like export restriction or
war or embargo then in that case the
political risk will come in picture yes
harid it is somewhat similar to ecgc but
certain minor differences I will bring
it to notice in during the tenor of this
Pol during the tener of this
presentation uh you can move on to the
next slide
yes so let's understand what are the
benefits of uh insurance policy first of
all it takes care of your of your bad
debts as it acts as a protection of the
bad debts which you will incur during
the program on is on secondly uh it
helps you to increase your top line by
exploring new markets uh see a a good
strategy to go in New Markets is to give
credit to the new buyers which you
identify in these markets and before
giving a credit you may not know who are
those and that is where you can keep a
Reliance on this trade Cent insurance
policy because with having this program
you can share the basic details of the
buyers with the insurance company
insurance company to underwrite those
and get back to you on what best what
best exposures you can take on these set
of buyers and once you based on the
recommendation of the insurance company
if there are any delinquencies if there
there are any bad Debs if there is a
event of insolvency the insurance
company will make good these losses up
to the certain Indemnity level based on
program program to
programs the next aspect which uh it
benefits is uh borrowing limits or
access to better borrowing in the
markets while it is uh developed in
international markets Credit Insurance
is an important tool it acts as a
collateral while taking working capital
facilities or trade Finance lines and
slowly and steadily it is picking up in
Indian markets also uh in short to tell
that if you are availing factoring
programs invoice discounting programs or
any other similar trade Finance related
program then you can use this trade
grade insurance program as a suitable
collateral while negotiating with bank
and you may at times get a facility
without giving any additional collateral
also how that would work is under this
program we would add the respective Bank
as a beneficiary of the program
beneficiary of the policy which means in
case of a claim scenario and the bank
has already financed against those
receivables then the claim can be
directly paid to bank with the consent
of the insured so that way it can help
you for better borrowing the next is
credit information resource so we are
having a database of more than
13,000 buyers uh across the world and
that resource would be available when we
say available based on your request we
will share the information that access
is not for the entire buyers but with
whom you're going to deal with respect
to those buyers information will be
shared with you on what is their credit
quality and how much exposure you can
take an add-on with this product is a
collection services so we once you have
this program in place once you have this
policy in place we also provide you
collection Services if there is any
delay in payment then we have our
in-house te recovery team which would
work closely with you in recovering that
amount and and that also will have a
defined timeline within that timeline
whatever is recovered that will reduce
the debt and subsequently if anti
recovery is not happened then the
insurance company will pay it at the
form of a claim there are certain rules
attached to this Credit Insurance
programs one is you are only covering
the unsecured receivable so you can you
might be doing business on say Advance
or LC letter of credit but however only
those which are having open exposure
where they don't have any sort of
collaterals such type of receivables are
covered the next is we are covering
basically two risk one is credit risk
credit risk involves insolvency and
protracted default that is delay in
payment Beyond acceptable time limit and
third is political risk that is because
because of Any adverse political events
resulting into delay in payment that can
be covered under the program the third
important aspect to understand where it
differentiates with ecgc is we are here
offering a whole turnover policy that is
an entire receivable of wherever there
is a credit offered that is covered
under one program just to add uh that
domestic and Export domestic sales as
export sales can also be covered under
one program on a standalone basis you
can take only exports on a standard
basis if you require you can only take
domestic also so three combination is
possible domestic export and a
collectively domestic export together in
one policy but when we once you say that
I want to cover this particular product
then all those all the rebl in relation
to that particular product needs to be
covered under the program the your
existing list of buyers will be covered
from the date of inception and your you
can keep on ADD adding new buyers in the
program during the tenure of the policy
just by giving their basic details like
name address their your payment terms
your estimated exposure which you want
to take and your total turnover with
that particular buyer for the given
period of the policy based on that you
can keep on adding the buyer in the
program and once it is approved you can
start supplying Goods to them premium is
charged on the turnover basis so you
have to estimate it's an annual program
you have to estimate your turnover for
for the next one year and based on that
we you can pay the premium the last
important rule here is you have to get
credit limits on all the buyers so the
buyers which are covered under the
program you need to share those basic
details with them and get your exposures
covered with insurance company you can
once initially once you start the
program all your buyers existing buyers
will be covered and as in when you add
new buyers they will get added to the
program
next slide
please certain features to understand
here so Indemnity here is 90% when we
say Indemnity we are talking about say
if your invoice value is say 100 rupees
up to 90 rupees will be made good by the
insurance company and that will be
defined before the Inception of the
program that what are the indemnity
levels insurance company is
providing then we have a concept of
minimum premium because this is an
estimated turnover you may or may not
achieve that turnover that is why we
keep a minimum premium concept say for
example you wanted to take a program for
100 crores and we say that okay uh we
would collect or we would incept the
program by only collecting 80% of the
premium so you'll be technically
covering 80 crores as a turnover but we
will take periodic declarations from you
quarterly say and say at the end of two
quarters three quarters if you're close
to 80 crores then we will come back and
request you to estimate the turnover for
the balance uh period of the policy you
can pay that premium uh and cover your
future shipments here estimated turnover
refers only to your credit sales of the
company so you need to make sure that
when you're giving any Declaration of
your turnover you need not include the
turnover of the company you need to
specifically give turnover only of the
credit sales which you have done maximum
limit of liability which is in other
insurance product it is called as some
insured we in this product we call as
maximum limit of liability that is
nothing but the total claims which we
pay for the tenure of the policy in one
single policy multiple claims insurance
company will keep on paying the premium
insurance going keep on paying the
claims till the time the complete sum
inur is exhausted and the sum insured is
structured as a multiple of your minimum
premium just to give you an example say
for example 100 crores is your turnover
and we charge say 10 lakhs premium for
your 100 crores covering your 100 CR
sales and multiple of that say 50 times
of 10 lakhs becomes your sum insured so
five crores is a sum ins short of the
program whatever invoices you issue
during that one year will is covered
under the program and multiple buyers
fail insurance company will keep on
paying the claim till the time 5 course
is exhausted it is linked to your
premium it is linked to your turnover so
that in case if your turnover increases
you'll end up paying additional premium
and accordingly your some insur will
increase for instance if your turnover
from 100 cres becomes 200 crores you
from 10 lakhs you pay additional 10
lakhs your total premium becomes 20
lakhs 50 times of that becomes 10 crores
so for your Su insure when you started
the program was five crores over a
period of time as you do more business
and add new buyers probably or do more
business with your existing buyers it it
will increase to 10 20 crores that way
it is a automatic chain which will help
you to uh make optimize use of this
policy next concept is maximum credit
period as I pointed out earlier if a
delayed payment a timeline is defined so
for in general this is 120 days uh
depending on your cycle depending on
your credit period it can be adjusted to
say 150 180 210 240 270 days also but at
the Inception of the program you need to
Define that what is the General Credit
period you offer we will put some markup
on that because you will also need some
time to talk to buyer and take the
payment from them so we will put some
market and according to maximum credit
period will be defined maximum
notification period that is a 30 days
more than the maximum credit period this
timeline is provided to file the or to
file the claim with the insurance
company then buyer wise credit limit to
be obtained for each buyer you need to
make sure wherever you're extending
credit you have a buyer limit in place
uh for that we have an online portal
where you can see all the buyers which
are covered and the exposure which
insurance company is obliged to take in
case if you are finding the the limits
requested as short you can make multiple
requests during the 10 of the policy to
increase the limits and then you can
take uh take the addition limits and
subsequently you can do business with
them then credit limit here rep
represents the maximum exposure which
are going to have on that particular
buyer while we understand at the
Inception you might think of X but if if
the business picks up that you might
your requirement might increase from X
to X Plus y but you can make that
request when the policy is going on next
slide
please there are some questions coming
on I take up subsequently once uh it is
uh once the presentation is
completed now certain exclusions uh
which we need to understand here uh
General train disputes are uh excluded
from this policy or I'll say it will be
suspended the claim would be suspended
till the time the trade disputes are
resolved next is your own sales to
subsidiary and Associate companies are
not covered however in this case we
cover the end buyer for example if you
have uh if you have an end entity based
in US you are you're you're exporting
from here to us entity and then us
entity is subsequently supplying to the
end customers there in that case we can
cover Indian entity as well as your us
entity as insured so Indian entty will
become insured the US en will become
additionally insured and we can cover
the local sales which your us entity do
in US market so that way we are not
covering your first leg that is sale
from parent entity to subsidary but we
can cover subsidiary sales to the end
customers then sale sales made under
letter of credit so LC's are considered
as secured instrument and that is why
you need not cover however just from an
information perspective in case if
you're dealing with LC's of not uh MNC
Banks then you have an option to
approach insurance company and request
to cover the LC Bank also in that case
we are basically covering the default
risk of the bank that if the bank is not
able to make honor the payment as per
the due date then the claim would be
covered otherwise in general we don't
cover letter of credit Sal as advanced
payment there is no element of uh credit
involved so we did not cover that sales
to individuals and for non-commercial
use are not covered see here we are
talking about uh private limited
companies limited companies
proprietorship and partnership these are
the four constitutions which are covered
under the program individuals like me
and you would if you're making sales to
them then that would not be
covered then consequential losses so if
your invoice is having an element of say
penalty clause or interest clause on
late of payment such type of uh
coverages would not be there we would be
only basically covering the principal
amount and in case if any GST if it is
applicable in local sales then GST will
also be covered whatever credit limit we
have set insurance compan is responsible
up to that amount if you do business
anything above that that loss would be
completely need to be absorbed by the
insured then nuclear risk and a war
between five Power Nations if that event
happens or we technically say it as
nuclear war in that case this cover
would be suspended and lastly loss due
to foreign currency fluctuation so you
understand that once you give a credit
period uh the currency exchange rate
would be different at the time of
shipment and the currency rate would be
different at the time of receipt of
money or if there is a delay in payment
there will be further uh differences but
we are not taking care of any currency
differences we'll be only talking about
the principal amount and U if any
exchange rate in case of a claim we will
stick to Reserve Bank of India's
exchange rate as per the respective date
of invoice and the respective date of du
due date now we can move on to the next
slide
please so this is the claim timeline
which need to be uh understood in detail
uh as I told you earlier maximum credit
period is the timeline within which it
is expected that you should get the
money from the insurance from the buyer
if you are not getting the money in the
next 30 days you are filing a claim with
the insurance company in case of a
protracted default once you file a claim
there is a 150 days waiting period so
what what happens in this 150 days
waiting period insurance company has an
in-house debt recovery team so just to
add here uh we work with multiple
reinsurers and these reinsurers are
present in your respective buyers Home
Country so they they have capabilities
to locally approach the buyers and try
to recover that money so this 150 days
is the timeline allowed to them so that
they can uh amicably get the money from
the uh from your buyer and in this 150
days whatever recovered that will reduce
the debt subsequently after the
completion of 150 days whatever is the
situation if no recovery or partial
recovery 90% of your outstanding amount
will be paid by the insurance company in
the form of a claim in next 30 days so
this was about a protracted default in
case of insolvency there is no concept
of claims waiting period once you file a
claim once you file an old you next 30
days the claim is
processed yes next slide please
please yes claim filing documents what
all information is required first is the
claim form which will become a part of a
policy document then your invoice copies
we need to submit your statement of
accounts that is your account statement
in relation to that particular buyer
needs to be shared in case you follow a
practice of balance confirmation
periodically then your latest balance
confirmation with that particular buyer
can be shared
proof of delivery that is shipping Bill
eBay bill that can be shared purchase
order sales contract if your business uh
has this practice of taking purchase
order or sales contract that can be
shared with the insurance company in
case because for some material uh issues
if there is any debit note or credit
note shared that can also be shared with
the insurance company during during the
time period when you have made any
follow-ups those followup Communications
can also be shared with insurance
company for their
future reference in case we want to go
legal against them and based on all
these documents in case if we need any
additional document we can put a request
to you for sharing any additional
information now let's move on to the
next slide
please so cost involved this is a very
important slide because most of the
times we understand that if a premium is
paid then entire coverage would be there
so in this policy there is there are
multiple cost which is one is premium
which is basically towards the risk
which you are taking the next we are
talking about the credit limit fees
credit limit fees is nothing but uh fees
of underwriting the buyers the portfolio
buyers which are getting underwritten
the reason we we are charging this Fe
over and above premium is because this
is an altogether different service which
we are taking we have tied up with all
the big data management companies across
the globe who procure the data available
in the local market and they've submit
to us in the format in which we want to
underwrite and we stick to tat also so
for example if it's if it's a private
limited company we have a tat of two
days in two days we would
comeing the name of the insured or
insurance or the insured and we check
whether such a business is available or
there or not along with that we also
have a system or portal which which is
which you will have an access where you
which can be used seamlessly it will be
linked to your email ID so once you put
a request there the information will be
shared with the underwriter
underwriter's assessment will be shared
with you on the email you need not open
that portal again and again so that is
why all this backend cost uh is uh is
charged separately over and above
premium the next is the intervention
fees intervention fees is applicable
when you file a claim to make sure that
we we see genuine claims however if you
are using the online portals this invent
intervention fees is not applicable and
lastly The Collection fees so collection
fees here we are talking about as you
heard that the indemnity levels are 90%
the 10% is the loss which insured is
expected to absorb and similarly when it
comes to collection fees 90% of the
collection fees is absorbed by the
insurance company 10% of such fees is
chargeable to the insured however this
these charges are very nominal because
we have this we have a big team which
supports us globally so this charges the
insurance contribution will be
irrespective of the loan amount it is
some in, rupees I'll say uh below below
one lakh rup below 50,000 rupes what is
the collection charges which would be
chargeable to insured irrespective of
whatever amount
outstanding yes next slide please
hello yeah you can move on to the next
slide sorry the earlier slide I think
Sachin meant the earlier slide yeah
competencies
okay uh actually and I am not able to I
able to see the previous slide only if
it is changed then uh this slide talks
about competencies of IC lot so we have
been writing this business from last 20
years you can say since Inception of
this product in Indian
markets and we have been working with
very strong reinsurers here and getting
their expertise in India as of now
around 8,000 to 9,000 buyers are there
in our portfolio with 13,000 crores of
exposure a very strong reinsurance
support we have a dedicated team at
Regional level also to support on how
how you can get best out of these
policies and in last two years we have
paid around 144 claims uh which is
roughly about 65 crores uh in last two
years so that is how uh this product has
been evolved and that is how I lomad is
a front runner as far as private
insurance policies private insurance
product a private insurance or service
providers as ConEd in relation to this
product uh I think this was the last
slide that's it from my side I'll just
take up the questions if
yeah so there was one more question uh
asked during the session uh that was
whether we cover or what is what are our
claims in in relation to Sri Lanka
Bangladesh Israel Gaza and Ukraine and
Russia so just to point out it has been
some time we are not taking any
exposures on these countries as of now
we are still open for uh Israel we had a
good exposure when uh Russia Ukraine war
happened and we paid certain uh amount
of claims for Russian buyers also
however subsequently we are able to
recover
that now how is the sales increased by
identifying buyers uh so sushmita here
you go to New Markets and you explore
you give credit to them you you add on
new customers in your portfolio by
giving credit whereas the default risk
is transferred to the insurance company
that is how you can add new buyers and
increase your sales what is the minimum
premium amount or minimum turnover to be
considered for Credit Insurance we are
looking at around 30 to 40 crores as a
minimum premium for this program and
minimum turnover for this program and
minimum premium we can go say seven to
eight lakhs for a program also however
we need to focus that it's a whole
turnover policy so thank you so much r g
and Sachin G I'll just hand out this
forum to Naman n kindly take for yeah
thank you thank you very much it is
indeed my pleasure to propose a formal
vote of thanks for this webinar our
sincere thanks to all the participants
for being with us for this important
webinar we hope that your session was
insightful and uh knowledge and reaching
for all the participants you must have
taken advantage of expertise and
experience of our speakers our special
thanks to Mr pramode buan and Mr Sachin
Sho for addressing all the participants
and addressing all the queries of the
members uh with your permissions some of
the participants are asking for the PPD
soft copy as well so we request you to
share it with us so that we can disate
among the
participants uh we once again thank you
all the participants and we look forward
for many more webinar in the future to
know more about the upcoming activities
of Plex Cil kindly do follow And
subscribe the social media channel of
Plex Cil you can also write to the all
the nearest office we do have our
offices in uh head office in Mumbai we
do have office in Chennai Kata Delhi as
well as in Gujarat at Amad we look
forward for many more interaction in
future thank you for being with us once
again have a good day ahead thank you
thank you thank you so much thank you by